<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>TheThaiBase.com - Ace</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="feeds/ace.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2024-04-24T00:00:00+07:00</updated><entry><title>Thailand Visa Guide (2025) : Everything You Need to Know</title><link href="thailand-visa-guide-2025-everything-you-need-to-know.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-04-24T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2024-04-24T00:00:00+07:00</updated><author><name>Ace</name></author><id>tag:None,2024-04-24:thailand-visa-guide-2025-everything-you-need-to-know.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A breakdown of long-stay, retirement, nomad, and LTR visa options.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="hero-banner"&gt;
  &lt;img
    src="/images/thailand_visa_guide_cover.jpg"
    alt="Thailand Visa Guide"
    class="hero-img"
  &gt;
  &lt;div class="hero-content"&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Thailand Visa Guide (2025)&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Everything you need to know to stay legal and stress-free&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigating Thailand’s visa regulations can be challenging. Here's your simplified guide to Thailand’s visa types for expats, digital nomads, and retirees in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Visa-Free Entry (Tourist Visa Exemption)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duration: 30 days (extendable once for 30 additional days)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who it’s for: Tourists and short-term digital nomads&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements: Passport valid for at least 6 months, return ticket or onward journey proof&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Tourist Visa (TR Visa)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duration: 60 days (extendable for 30 additional days)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who it’s for: Tourists and digital nomads exploring Thailand for a longer stay&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements: Passport, completed visa application, proof of funds, hotel reservations, return or onward ticket&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Education (ED) Visa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duration: 90 days, renewable for 1 year total&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who it’s for: Students, language learners, or training participants&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements: Enrollment documents from an accredited school, passport, proof of funds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Business (Non-Immigrant B) Visa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duration: 90 days, extendable to 1 year with work permit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who it’s for: Entrepreneurs, business owners, and workers employed by Thai companies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements: Passport, employment letter, business documents, evidence of financial stability&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Retirement (Non-Immigrant O-A &amp;amp; O-X) Visa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duration: 1 year (O-A), up to 10 years (O-X)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who it’s for: Retirees aged 50 or above&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements: Proof of retirement funds (THB 800,000 in Thai bank or monthly income of THB 65,000), health insurance, medical certificate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Digital Nomad / Long-Term Residency (LTR) Visa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duration: Up to 10 years (renewable every 5 years)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who it’s for: Remote workers, digital nomads, professionals, and wealthy individuals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements: Proof of remote work or employment overseas, minimum income requirement (around USD 40,000/year), health insurance coverage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Tips:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extensions: Many visas can be extended at local immigration offices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;90-day Reporting: All long-term visa holders must report their residence every 90 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visa Runs: Short-term visitors must leave Thailand briefly to reset their stay unless switching to another visa type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overstay Penalties: Severe fines and possible bans apply for overstays; always maintain visa validity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thailand’s visa policies can change, so always check the latest information from your local Thai embassy or consulate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay informed, stay legal, and enjoy your life in the Land of Smiles!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Articles"></category><category term="visas"></category><category term="thailand"></category><category term="expat"></category></entry></feed>